## SANTIAGO CADAVID

#### **Biomedical Engineer**

Auckland, New Zealand

#### **PROFILE**

I am a Biomedical Engineer with experience measuring, acquiring and processing human physiological signals, controlling environmental variables in hospital sensors and installing, calibrating, repairing and inspecting medical equipment. I have a good understanding of a wide range of medical devices, electronics principles and medical concepts, which allow me to liaise between the clinical personnel and engineers making me an influential member of cross-functional teams. On top of my technical background, I have a general understanding of ICT management and digital transformation at a corporate level with an emphasis on innovation and marketing due to my recent studies in Technology Management.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### **Biomedical Engineer**

**BV** Medical

October 2020 - Currently

- Q Auckland, N7
- Performs preventive/scheduled maintenance on medical devices, and installs, calibrates, repairs and inspects medical equipment.
- Participates with the team on medical equipment evaluations, installations and upgrades, including software revision.
- Teaches clinical and technical staff of the medical centres on the operation, safe use, care and handling, and user maintenance procedures for medical equipment.
- Performs equipment repairs of substantial difficulty to a level requiring generic test instrumentation, or diagnostic software.
- Conducts complete performance assurance and electrical safety testing.
- Determines the need to remove and/or replace malfunctioning medical devices from service and implements accordingly.

## Assistant manager

MK RD Limited

**August 2018 – October 2020** 

**Q** Auckland, NZ

# Field service engineer Iforware S.A.S.

- ♥ Medellín, Colombia
- To design and create prototypes using open-source electronic prototyping platforms (i.e. Arduino) and commercial electronics.
- To operate with a variety of analog and digital transducers (temperature, humidity, dew point, gas concentration) for industrial and healthcare applications.
- To design and develop printed circuit boards (PCB) and assemble them.
- To develop hardware of traceability, telemetry and control.
- To support software tests in traceability, telemetry and control.
- To keep the correct operation of sensors and the telemetry system that were installed in hospitals and laboratories.

## **SKILLS**

Medical Devices Electrical/Electronics

New enterprise development

Technology Marketing

Digital signal acquisition

Digital signal processing

Surface electromyography

Swallowing disorders

Academic and clinical research

Physics

General Hospital Monitoring
Polygraph Monitoring
Cardiovascular Therapeutic
Anesthesiology Therapeutic
Physical Medicine Therapeutic
Surgical
Dental Devices
Radiology Diagnostic



Microsoft Office MATLAB LabChart
LaTeX Arduino PCB design software
HTML Fusion 360

Curious A innate talent to teach
Innovative Approachable attitude

## **LANGUAGES**

Commitment

English Spanish



## **EDUCATION**

BSc(Eng) Biomedical Engineering
Instituto Tecnológico Metropolitano (ITM)

**2012 - 2017** 

Diploma level 7 in Technology Management Aspire2 International (New Zealand)

**2017 - 2018** 

### RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

#### Research Fellow

#### Instituto Tecnológico Metropolitano

- To evaluate different kinds of electrodes and their position configurations to improve the signal-noise ratio during surface electromyography (sEMG) signal acquisition.
- Acquisition of sEMG signals in healthy people during motor gestures involved during swallowing.
- To evaluate the activation patterns of each motor gesture performed.
- To prepare and carry out a workshop for students from different universities about electromyography and its applications.

## **PUBLICATIONS**

#### Journal Articles

- Cadavid-Arboleda, Santiago et al. (2017). "Assessment of Surface Electromyography During Orofacial Praxis in Healthy Subjects". In: VII Latin American Congress on Biomedical Engineering CLAIB 2016, Bucaramanga, Santander, Colombia, October 26th -28th, 2016 60, pp. 165–168. DOI: 10.1007/978-981-10-4086-3. URL: http://link.springer.com/10.1007/978-981-10-4086-3.
- Cantillo-Mackenzie, German et al. (2017). "Surface
  Electromyographic Characterization of Five Orofacial Ideomotor
  Praxis in 20 Healthy Individuals". In: VII Latin American Congress on
  Biomedical Engineering CLAIB 2016, Bucaramanga, Santander, Colombia,
  October 26th -28th, 2016 60, pp. 221-224. DOI:
  10.1007/978-981-10-4086-3. URL:
  http://link.springer.com/10.1007/978-981-10-4086-3.
- Restrepo-Agudelo, Sebastian et al. (2017). "Improving surface EMG burst detection in infrahyoid muscles during swallowing using digital filters and discrete wavelet analysis". In: Journal of Electromyography and Kinesiology 35, pp. 1–8. ISSN: 10506411. DOI: 10.1016/j.jelekin.2017.05.001. URL: http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1050641116302991.

## ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

 Electrical Appliance Serviceperson (EAS) / Credential ID EAS-TLC 154510

## REFERENCES

References available upon request.